VIRAL PATEL

(647)937-1043 | viralpatel1043@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/viral1043 | https://recroviral.github.io/vp/

Summary

Seeking a career which is challenging, innovative and competitive, offering excellent opportunities. Hardware and Software developer over 2 years of college experience working in Research and Software Development.

Technical Skills

- C++ Python Django Framework HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap MATLAB AWS IoT Cloud Platform
- VMWARE Docker Kubernetes Microsoft SQL Server Git GitHub TCP/IP Protocol WAN LAN
- Windows Ubuntu/UNIX MS Office Suite

Professional Experience

April 2019 –

Field Service Technician

Bell Technical Solutions, Markham

- Present
- Installation, maintenance, and repair of copper-based telecommunications equipment, product and services.
- Provide an exceptional customer experience for our clients.
- Troubleshoots complex telecommunications products and system.
- Work independently and assist other technicians while in the field.
- Observe and follow all company health and Safety rules and policies.

Jan 2019 – March 2019

Computer Technician

SCI White Gloves, Mississauga

- Install / Upgrade the windows servers, printers and mobile devices.
- Setup LAN network and run the scripts to troubleshoot the problem.
- Building and maintaining web-based reports and dashboards.

Sept 2015 – Dec 2016

Project Engineer

Trom Sloar, Gujarat, India

- Lead field team of 5 employees and handling Installation, commissioning, testing related to each project.
- Prepare compelling presentation to graphically explain each project issue and opportunities.

Education

May 2017 - Dec 2018 June 2011 - May 2015 **Embedded System Design Engineering**

Lambton College, Toronto, ON

Bachelor's Degree in Electrical Engineering

Ganpat University, India

Education Projects

- Building a Personal Portfolio with Django and deploy on AWS cloud server.
- Deploying Containerized web application on AWS using Docker and Kubernetes
- Waste Management System using IoT Application with Smart compactor
- Parcel Box Keeper using secure barcode authentication system
- Face and Eye detection using raspberry CAM

Volunteer Experience

- Was active member of Yuva Unstoppable NGO which helped poor students in nearby villages of Ahmedabad
- Worked with Tutoring Center in Lambton college as Peer Tutor during Sept 2018 to Dec 2018

Award

New Hire "Great Start" award

Bell Technical Solutions (BTS)

June 2019